A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Countries, Series E FA341
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Scotland
  Scotland
  - Scotland, 1955-1970 (Box 60, Folder 513)
    Appeals, requests for jobs, invitations.
- Soviet Union
  Soviet Union
  - Soviet Union, 1946-1971 (Box 60, Folder 514)
    Miscellaneous clippings; printed material; appeal; letter of thanks for gifts from Nikita Khrushchev, 1959.
- Spain
  Spain
  - Spain - General Correspondence (A-E), 1958-1971 (Box 61, Folder 515)
    General appeals. Miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Spain - General Correspondence (F-G), 1958-1971 (Box 61, Folder 516)
  - Spain - General Correspondence (H-P), 1958-1971 (Box 61, Folder 517)
  - Spain - General Correspondence (Q-S), 1958-1971 (Box 61, Folder 518)
  - Spain - General Correspondence (T-Z), 1958-1971 (Box 61, Folder 519)
  - Spain - Colleges and Schools, 1956-1958 (Box 61, Folder 520)
  - Spain - Gonzales-Robles, Luis, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 521)
    Director of Spanish Museum of Contemporary Art. One 1969 letter.
- Sweden
  Sweden
  - Sweden, 1932-1971 (Box 61, Folder 522)
    Appeals; greetings; correspondence with Gosta Nisser, 1934; miscellaneous requests.
- Switzerland
  Switzerland
  - Switzerland - General Correspondence (A-E), 1946-1971 (Box 62, Folder 523)
    Mostly appeals; miscellaneous greetings; previous to 1958 destroyed.
  - Switzerland - General Correspondence (F-J), 1946-1971 (Box 62, Folder 524)
  - Switzerland - General Correspondence (K-R), 1946-1971 (Box 62, Folder 525)
  - Switzerland - General Correspondence (S-Z), 1946-1971 (Box 62, Folder 526)
  - Switzerland - Rosanes Y Perez-Pisanti, Elisa (Elisa Mapely), 1965-1969 (Box 62, Folder 527)
    Blind woman; appeals on behalf of the Swiss Foundation to Prevent and Combat Blindness. All declined.
- Syria
  Syria
  - Syria, 1960-1965 (Box 62, Folder 528)
    Miscellaneous; appeals declined.
- Taiwan
  Taiwan
  - Taiwan, 1968-1971 (Box 62, Folder 529)
- Thailand
  Thailand
  - Thailand, 1931-1969 (Box 62, Folder 530)
    1931 letter re: visit of King. Appeals, declined. Invitation and thanks.
- Tunisia
  Tunisia
  - Tunisia, 1958-1964 (Box 62, Folder 531)
    Miscellaneous correspondence and appeals - declined.
- Turkey
  Turkey
  - Turkey, 1958-1969 (Box 62, Folder 532)
    Memo on government. Appeals, declined. Miscellaneous correspondence.
- Uruguay
  Uruguay
  - Uruguay - General Correspondence (A-G), 1945-1971 (Box 63, Folder 533)
    Miscellaneous and appeals.
  - Uruguay - General Correspondence (H-Z), 1945-1971 (Box 63, Folder 534)
  - Uruguay - Adventist Institute of Uruguay, 1952-1955 (Box 63, Folder 535)
  - Uruguay - Blanco, Juan Carlos, 1947-1950 (Box 63, Folder 536)
    Ambassador to United States from Uruguay. Miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Uruguay - Figari, Pedro, 1946 (Box 63, Folder 537)
    Artist, correspondence re: exhibit.
  - Uruguay - Legislation, 1947 (Box 63, Folder 538)
    Memos re: one piece of legislation affecting investment companies.
  - Uruguay - McNutt, Albert H. and Maria Helena (Serrato), 1948-1968 (Box 63, Folder 539)
    Correspondence re: visits Mrs. McNutt's father Jose Serrato, investment opportunity, appointment of Mrs. McNutt's nephew to ministry post.
  - Uruguay - Pons, Julio, 1942-1949 (Box 63, Folder 540)
    Correspondence re: labor conference and financing of projects.
  - Uruguay - Sacikauskas, Francisco, 1958 (Box 63, Folder 541)
    Letters from above re: Communism and threat of the Soviet Union in South America; no replies sent.
  - Uruguay - Schools, 1950 (Box 63, Folder 542)
    Appeal to establish American school in Uruguay. Declined.
- Venezuela
  Venezuela
  - Venezuela - General, 1947-1962 (Box 63, Folder 543)
    Clippings; miscellaneous correspondence re: International Basic Economy Corporation studies, economic development, politics.
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (A), 1947-1970 (Box 64, Folder 544)
    Miscellaneous, mostly appeals - declined.
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (B), 1947-1970 (Box 64, Folder 545)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (C), 1947-1970 (Box 64, Folder 546)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (D), 1947-1970 (Box 64, Folder 547)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (E), 1947-1970 (Box 64, Folder 548)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (F), 1947-1970 (Box 64, Folder 549)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (G), 1950-1970 (Box 65, Folder 550)
    Appeals and miscellaneous.
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (H), 1949-1970 (Box 65, Folder 551)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (I), 1949-1971 (Box 65, Folder 552)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (J-K), 1948-1964 (Box 65, Folder 553)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (L), 1947-1971 (Box 65, Folder 554)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (M), 1947-1971 (Box 65, Folder 555)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (N), 1958-1968 (Box 65, Folder 556)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (O), 1959-1969 (Box 65, Folder 557)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (P), 1947-1971 (Box 66, Folder 558)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (Q), 1948-1970 (Box 66, Folder 559)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (R), 1947-1971 (Box 66, Folder 560)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (S), 1940-1971 (Box 66, Folder 561)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (T), 1948-1970 (Box 66, Folder 562)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (U-V), 1942-1969 (Box 66, Folder 563)
  - Venezuela - General Correspondence (Y-Z), 1958-1971 (Box 66, Folder 564)
  - Venezuela - Accion, 1961-1967 (Box 66, Folder 565)
    Americans for Community Cooperation in Other Nations; descriptive materia, Rockefeller Brothers Fund grant mentioned. Rodman C. Rockefeller on Board of Directors.
  - Venezuela - Accion Democratica, 1947-1953 (Box 66, Folder 566)
    Committee for Democratic Action. Appeals declined; printed material.
  - Venezuela - Aleman Sucre, Eladio, 1948-1969 (Box 67, Folder 567)
    Requests for support of proposals, no help given.
  - Venezuela - American Church in Caracas, 1947 (Box 67, Folder 568)
    Request for aid.
  - Venezuela - Anglade, Carlos, 1947-1954 (Box 67, Folder 569)
    Requests for letters of recommendation for son and miscellaneous.
  - Venezuela - Araujo, Antonio M., Dr., 1951 (Box 67, Folder 570)
    Served as Venezuelan Ambassador to United States. Resigned May 23, 1952.
  - Venezuela - Arraiz, Antonio, 1948-1957 (Box 67, Folder 571)
    Articles written by Arraiz.
  - Venezuela - Avila Hotel, 1950 (Box 67, Folder 572)
    One letter re: activity of hotel, 1950.
  - Venezuela - Ball, R. R., Dr., 1945-1961 (Box 67, Folder 573)
    Correspondence re: son's education; connected with Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) in Caracas and miscellaneous.
  - Venezuela - Betancourt, Romulo, 1946-1969 (Box 67, Folder 574)
    Clippings; Betancourt served as President; Betancourt cables; miscellaneous correspondence; gift of autograph; memo and letter analyzing Betancourt's position politically; visit to United States in 1963.
  - Venezuela - Betancourt, Romulo - Printed Material, 1946-1969 (Box 67, Folder 575)
    On and by Betancourt.
  - Venezuela - Bolivar Letter, October 24, 1925, 1965-1971 (Box 67, Folder 576)
    Correspondence re: letter written by Bolivar and owned by NAR; typewritten copies; photographs on infra-red film; letter given to Bolivarian Society of Venezuela. Request for NAR to buy Bolivar's sword declined.
  - Venezuela - Bottome, Robert and Mrs., 1949-1968 (Box 68, Folder 577)
    Correspondence re: EMPRO, an investment company, and Centro Venezolano-Americano
  - Venezuela - Boulton, John William, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 578)
    NAR letters re: admission to New York State College of Agriculture and Cornell for above's son.
  - Venezuela - Caldera, Rafael, Dr., President, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 579)
    NAR congratulations on election to Presidency.
  - Venezuela - Carnevali, Gonzalo, 1947-1948 (Box 68, Folder 580)
    Served as Venezuelan Ambassador to United States, miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Venezuela - Cetand, Juan de Dios, 1948 (Box 68, Folder 581)
    Requests for aid and letters re: Venezuelan Basic Economy Corporation's work.
  - Venezuela - Churches, 1949-1969 (Box 68, Folder 582)
  - Venezuela - Coles, William F. (Coles & Valera), 1947-1970 (Box 68, Folder 583)
    Clippings; NAR's representative in Venezuela; miscellaneous correspondence re: Venezuelan Basic Economy Corporation, trips, meetings, etc.
  - Venezuela - Colleges, 1947-1968 (Box 68, Folder 584)
  - Venezuela - Corporacion Venezolana de Fomento (Venezuela Development Corporation), 1946-1953 (Box 68, Folder 585)
    Miscellaneous; nothing of substance.
  - Venezuela - Delgado Chalbaud, Carlos, 1949 (Box 68, Folder 586)
    Resume and memo on conversation.
  - Venezuela - Earthquake, 1967 (Box 68, Folder 587)
    Clippings and telegram re: earthquake.
  - Venezuela - Falcon Briceno, M. A., 1947-1960 (Box 68, Folder 588)
    Correspondence re: meetings, visits, payment for wife's care during ill health; attached to Venezuelan Embassy, Washington, D. C.
  - Venezuela - Gallegos, Romulo, Sr. Don, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 589)
  - Venezuela - Gallegos, Romulo, Sr. Don - Visit to United States, July, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 590)
    Elected president, 1947; in exile, 1949. Visit to United States, 1948; correspondence re: preparation, itinerary, luncheons, dinner in Gallegos's honor.
  - Venezuela - Gomez Ruiz, Luis E., 1950-1967 (Box 69, Folder 591)
    Served as Minister of Foreign Affairs; letters of thanks and miscellaneous correspondence. Died December 20, 1966.
  - Venezuela - Government, 1947-1971 (Box 69, Folder 592)
    Correspondence re: government, trading, politics, men in government; memos re: political situation, clippings.
  - Venezuela - Gran Sbana Syndicate, 1947 (Box 69, Folder 593)
    Second and third reports to subscribers.
  - Venezuela - Hospitals, 1948-1963 (Box 69, Folder 594)
    Appeals declined and miscellaneous.
  - Venezuela - Labor, 1947 (Box 69, Folder 595)
    Two letters re: labor developments.
  - Venezuela - Leoni, Raul, 1948-1965 (Box 69, Folder 596)
    Succeeded Betantcourt as President; miscellaneous correspondence and congratulations; little of substance.
  - Venezuela - Long, John R. y Associados, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 597)
    Report to Coporacion de Fomento.
  - Venezuela - Lope Bello, Xavier, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 598)
    Correspondence re: visits, gifts, letters of thanks and greetings, articles.
  - Venezuela - Maldonado, Ivan Dario, Jr., 1955-1971 (Box 69, Folder 599)
    Correspondence re: Invega, Inlaca, NAR-Maldonado partnership; and miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Venezuela - Mendoza, Carlos, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 600)
    President of Banco Central de Venezuela. Correspondence re: son's education. One letter re: sheep raising.
  - Venezuela - Mendoza Goiticoa, Eduardo, 1948-1969 (Box 69, Folder 601)
    Once Minister of Agriculture. Letter of introduction from NAR to Bob Kleberg (King Ranch) for above and miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Venezuela - Mendoza, Eugenio, 1941-1968 (Box 70, Folder 602)
    NAR contribution to Hospital Poliomielitico; correspondence re: family, Mendoza Foundation, speeches, activities, education for Mendoza children. Eugenio Mendoza was an industrialist and Minister of Development, 1943-1944; member of governing Junta, 1958.
  - Venezuela - Mendoza, Eugenio, Foundation, 1951-1968 (Box 70, Folder 603)
    Printed material; correspondence re: establishment of foundation and its projects with children and social programs.
  - Venezuela - Mendoza, Juan Simon, 1947-1948 (Box 70, Folder 604)
    Dealer in automobiles and machinery.
  - Venezuela - Mendoza, Lope, 1948-1961 (Box 70, Folder 605)
    Miscellaneous corrrespondence.
  - Venezuela - Mondolfi, Rodolfo, 1947-1969 (Box 70, Folder 606)
    Served as Executive Secretary of Venezuelan Basic Economy Corporation. Correspondence re: education of daughter, marriages of children.
  - Venezuela - Montilla, Ricardo, 1948-1968 (Box 70, Folder 607)
    Minister of Agriculture, 1948. Miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Venezuela - Oil, 1947-1953 (Box 70, Folder 608)
    Clippings and miscellaneous memo on oil production in Venezuela.
  - Venezuela - Oropeza Castillo, Alexander, 1947 (Box 70, Folder 609)
    Died December 28, 1964. President of Corporacion Venezuelana de Fomento.
  - Venezuela - Pares, Jose H., 1969-1971 (Box 70, Folder 610)
    Unsuccessful attempt to interest NAR in project of Seine Worlds Fair and peace monument. Eccentric son of Inlaca partner.
  - Venezuela - Parra-Perez, C., Dr., 1946-1961 (Box 71, Folder 611)
    Venezuelan Ambassador to France, 1946-1947. Served as Foreign Minister during WWII.
  - Venezuela - Perez Alfonso, J. P., 1947 (Box 71, Folder 612)
    Minister of Development, 1947.
  - Venezuela - Pietri, Alejandro, 1948-1953 (Box 71, Folder 613)
    Clippings, correspondence re: activities; associated with Standard Oil of New Jersey.
  - Venezuela - Printed Matter, 1945-1953 (Box 71, Folder 614)
    Clippings, pamphlets, etc.
  - Venezuela - Rangel Baez, Jose A., 1949 (Box 71, Folder 615)
  - Venezuela - Republic Democratic Union Party, 1949 (Box 71, Folder 616)
    One memo, 1949.
  - Venezuela - Schools, 1953-1971 (Box 71, Folder 617)
    Appeals; NAR response to New Bejuma Schools, others declined.
  - Venezuela - Schools, Nirgua Instituto Vocacional de Venezuela, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 618)
  - Venezuela - Stolk, Carlos Eduardo, 1950 (Box 71, Folder 619)
    Venezuelan Ambassador to United Nations. Reopened law practice, 1950. NAR letters of introduction.
  - Venezuela - Supermarkets, 1957 (Box 71, Folder 620)
    One memo re: gossip about NAR and supermarket policy.
  - Venezuela - Tejera Paris, Enrique, Dr., 1940-1968 (Box 71, Folder 621)
    Served as Governor of State of Sucre and Ambassador to United States, 1963-1968.
  - Venezuela - Tourism - National Convention, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 622)
    Report on the National Convention, 1966; NAR or representative invited.
  - Venezuela - Valera, Raul, 1958-1971 (Box 71, Folder 623)
    Miscellaneous correspondence. Served as Minister of Labor and Governor of Federal District.
  - Venezuela - Venezuelan Association of Women, 1951 (Box 71, Folder 624)
    Appeal for NAR contribution.
  - Venezuela - Venezuelan Baseball Team, 1950 (Box 72, Folder 625)
    Correspondence re: visit of team for Carrasquel Day, July 16, 1950 at Yankee Stadium; NAR contribution; photographs.
  - Venezuela - Venezuelan Trade Mission, 1950 (Box 72, Folder 626)
    NAR reception for mission members; purpose is to increase business and trade between Venezuela and United States; letters of thanks.
  - Venezuela - Villalba, Jovita, 1948 (Box 72, Folder 627)
    Head of Union Republicana Democratica, 1948. Member of Venezuelan National Congress. Memo.
  - Venezuela - Zuloaga, Pedro, Dr. and Mrs., 1950 (Box 72, Folder 628)
    Delegate to United Nations.
- Wales
  Wales
  - Wales - General Correspondence (A-Z), 1954-1971 (Box 72, Folder 629)
    Re: "the Welsh Nation" and one appeal.
- West Indies
  West Indies
  - West Indies, British and French, 1954-1971 (Box 72, Folder 630)
- West New Guinea
  - West New Guinea, West Papua, 1947-1971 (Box 72, Folder 631)
    Letter and printed material re: independence for West Papua.
- Yugoslavia
  Yugoslavia
  - Yugoslavia, 1952-1971 (Box 72, Folder 632)